John James Audubon Collection, 1788-1969: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 7: J. J. Audubon, as Subject: Pamphlets, Clippings, etc., 1851-1964; 16 folders
  - Exhibition catalogues, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Havell, engraver, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Re: elephant folio, Princeton University Library copy, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - List of Plates; Census of Elephant Folio, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Engraved plates. Dealers (catalogues with price-lists), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Florida, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Information about items in Princeton Collections, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Reproductions of Engraved Prints, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts. Letters, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Empty [Contains a note about Setter and Quails], dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - "Mill Grove" Audubon house in Pennsylvania, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Portraits of Elijah Slack & wife by J. J. A. (acquired by Princeton, ), 1964; 1 folder (Folder 13)
  - Portraits of J. J. A., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 14)
  - Oil Paintings, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 15)
  - Obituary by T. M. Brewer, in Boston Atlas, 1851; 1 folder (Folder 16)
- Series 8: Audubon Exhibition 1959: Correspondence, Catalogue and Publicity, Research Notes, 15 folders
  Consists of correspondence and information regarding the Audubon Exhibition in 1959.
  Except for correspondence with D. Speyer, correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Followed by unarranged documents and subseries, "Research Notes for Catalogue," which is arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence with D. Speyer, USIS, Paris, re: Paris exhibition, 1960; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - 1959 May 15-September, 1 folder (Folder 2)
    Items borrowed.
  - Correspondence A - E, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    Includes: Sylvia Beach, Geo. Dock, Jr.
  - Correspondence F - L, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    Includes: Alice Ford, W. H. Fries, Harvard.
  - Correspondence M - N, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    Includes: McCormick, H. Bradley Martin, National Audubon Society-NY, New Jersey Audubon Society, Harry Shaw Newman-old printshop, J. d'Arcy Northwood-curator, Audubon Shrine.
  - Correspondence O - Z, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    Includes: Benj. Page, Jr., Darthea Speyer (USIS, Paris), Stout, J. S. Williams.
  - Press Release; publicity; talks by H.C.R. on exhibition, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Thomas Birch painting of Mill Grove, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Leaflet, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Research Notes for Catalogue, dates not examined; 6 folders
    - II & supporting documentation, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - IV, V, VI., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - VII. N.J. paper money cf. no. 44, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - VIII - IX., dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - X, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - XVI. "Minnie's Land", dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 15)
- Series 9: Chronological List of Audubon's Bird Drawings, dates not examined; 1 box
  Based on the "List of Places, Comprising the Original Issue of Audubon's `The Birds of America,' With Notes Showing Where and When the Original Drawings Were Made," in S. C. Arthur, Audubon, 1937, Appendix E., p. 500 ff.
  Arthur's dating of the drawings is based chiefly on the annotations to be found on the originals, now in N.Y. Historical Society.
  Present card index compiled by Mrs. Julian P. Boyd, 1959. It was used as a basis for grouping Audubon bird plates according to place & date of the drawing, rather than by date of publication. Audubon exhibition, 1959.
  H. C. Rice
  - Chronological List of Audubon's Bird Drawings, dates not examined; 1 box
- 32101040679084 (Box 6)
- 32101040679043 (Box 1)
- 32101040679050 (Box 2)
- 32101047417801 (Volume 1)
- 32101047417793 (Volume 2)
- 32101047417785 (Volume 3)
- 32101047419013 (Volume 4)
- 32101047417777 (Volume 5)
- 32101047417769 (Volume 6)
- 32101040679068 (Box 3)
- 32101040679076 (Box 4)
- 32101040679092 (Box 5)